Guide to the Hisham Khatib Collection of photographic prints AD.MC.030
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Bethlehem, Jerusalem and Ramleh, ref152 (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
  - No.333 Eglise de la Nativité colonnade (Colonnade in the Church of the Nativity)., Circa 1870 - 1880; ref781; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
    Church of the Nativity; Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Religious Sites; Bethlehem; Palestine; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - No.333 Bethléem Église de Nativité colonnade (Colonnade in the Church of the Nativity)., Circa 1870 - 1880; ref782; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
    Churches; Church of the Nativity; Architecture; Buildings; Religious Sites; Bethlehem; Palestine; French Writing; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - No.334 Palestine Intérieur de l'Eglise de la Nativité a Bethlehem (Interior of the Church of the Nativity)., Circa 1870 - 1880; ref783; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
    Churches; Church of the Nativity; Architecture; Religious Sites; Bethlehem; Palestine; French Writing; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints
  - No.333 Colonnade de l'Église de la Nativité (Colonnade in the Church of the Nativity)., Circa 1870 - 1880; ref784; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
    Church of the Nativity; Churches; Architecture; Buildings; Religious Sites; Bethlehem; Palestine; French Writing; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - No.335 Grotte de la Nativité (Grotto of the Nativity)., Circa 1870 - 1880; ref785; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
    Caves; Church of the Nativity; Religious Sites; Bethlehem; Palestine; French Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Churches
  - No.242 Tour des 40 martyrs, Rameleh (A view of the Tower of the Forty Martyrs, White Mosque, Ramla)., Circa 1870 - 1880; ref786; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
    Ramla/ar-Ramlah; Landscapes; Buildings; White Mosque, Ramla; Religious Sites; Architecture; Mosques; Palestine; French Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Architecture
  - No.326 Jardin du roi, Rois XX-4, vallée de Gehenne, Jerusalem, Palestine (A view of Gehenna)., Circa 1870 - 1880; ref787; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
    Landscapes; Gehenna/Valley of Hinnom; Jerusalem; Palestine; Religious Sites; French Writing; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Mountains/Hills
  - No.1199 Ramleh, vue générale prise de la tour (A general view of Ramleh from the tower)., Circa 1870 - 1880; ref788; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
    Ramla/ar-Ramlah; Landscapes; Palestine; French Writing; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Cemeteries
  - No.1016 Maison de Simon le corroyeur (The House of Simon the Tanner)., Circa 1870 - 1880; ref789; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref154-ref193)
    Houses; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Palestine; Religious Sites; French Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Jaffa; Workers; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Albumen Prints
  - Original description of collection from Kisham Khatib's library., ref790; Bonfils, Felix
    Bethlehem; Jerusalem; Ramla/ar-Ramlah
- Palestine and Syria, ref194 (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
  Palestine; Architecture; Mosques; Buildings; Landscapes
  - Three buses on a roundabout by the coast with a menorah in the center., Circa 1930s - 1960s; ref195; Palphot, Tel Aviv; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Palestine; Buses; Streets/Roads; Coast; Beaches; Landscapes; Tel Aviv/Tall ʾabīb; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Mediterranean Sea; Transportation
  - Street view with Yarden Hotel in the foreground on the corner of Sderot Ben Gurion and Ben Yehuda Street, Tel Aviv., Circa 1930s - 1960s; ref196; Palphot, Tel Aviv; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Palestine; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Buildings; Hotels; Tel Aviv/Tall ʾabīb; Architecture; Transportation; Buses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Shops; Houses; Landscapes
  - View of a hilltop from a meadow., Circa 1940 - 1950s; ref197; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Landscapes; Palestine; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Mountains/Hills
  - People at VI Station of the Cross, Jerusalem., Circa 1940 - 1950s; ref198; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Buildings; Architecture; Jerusalem; Palestine; Religious Sites; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Boys; Streets/Roads; Food; Children; Group Portraits
  - Two women working with bowls., Circa 1940 - 1950s; ref199; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Women; Palestine; Household Appliances; Houses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Food; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress; Furnishings; Furnishings; Group Portraits
  - Aerial view of Dome of the Rock and Temple Mount, Circa 1940 - 1950s; ref200; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Jerusalem; Landscapes; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Palestine; Outdoors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Mountains/Hills
  - The Dome of the Rock with the Russian Church and Mount of olives in the background., Circa 1940 - 1950s; ref201; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Churches; Jerusalem; Religious Sites; Buildings; Palm Trees; Palestine; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Landscapes; Buildings; Houses; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem
  - Camels walking in front of a small domed building., Circa 1940 - 1950s; ref202; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Camels; Buildings; Men; Landscapes; Palestine; Architecture; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Palestine; Animals; Mountains/Hills; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - People walking and riding donkeys beside The Tower of David (Burj Dāwūd)., Circa 1940 - 1950s; ref203; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Landscapes; Tower of David/Burj Dāwūd (Jerusalem Citadel); Donkeys; Men; Architecture; Religious Sites; Palestine; Streets/Roads; Buses; Outdoors; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Transportation; Jerusalem
  - Women walking on Via Dolorosa, Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref204; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Women; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Jerusalem; Palestine; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Regional/National Dress
  - A clergyman in Garden of Gethsemane., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref205; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Gethsemane, Jerusalem; Gardens; Priests/Clergymen; Landscapes; Palestine; Jerusalem; Religious Sites; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - People walking on Via Dolorosa., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref206; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Streets/Roads; Men; Women; Children; Jerusalem; Palestine; Architecture; Buildings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Boys; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps
  - Interior of the Dome of the Rock., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref207; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Chandeliers; Religious Sites; Jerusalem; Palestine; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Tombs/Mausoleums; Mosques; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Aerial view of the Church of the Nativity and Manger Square, Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref208; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Bethlehem; Church of the Nativity; Palestine; Religious Sites; Architecture; Churches; Buildings; Landscapes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Photographic Prints
  - Three men in a workshop., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref209; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Men; Pottery; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Workers; Palestine; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
  - A park and a coastline., Circa 1930s - 1960s; ref210; Palphot, Tel Aviv; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Landscapes; Seas; Beaches; Children; Men; Women; Buildings; Palestine; Tel Aviv/Tall ʾabīb; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Streets/Roads; Parks
  - People walking on a path alongside a crowded beach., Circa 1930s - 1960s; ref211; Palphot, Tel Aviv; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Crowds; Men; Women; Children; Beaches; Palestine; Seas; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tel Aviv/Tall ʾabīb; Landscapes; Buildings; Architecture; Outdoors
  - View of the Church of All Nations and the Church of Mary Magdalene., Circa 1930s - 1960s; ref212; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Churches; Landscapes; Religious Sites; Architecture; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Jerusalem; Palestine; Outdoors; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Transportation; Church of Mary Magdalene, Jerusalem
  - Mounds of oranges in front of the Damascus Gate, Jerusalem., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref213; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Damascus Gate, Jerusalem; Jerusalem; Palestine; Men; Architecture; Buildings; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Outdoors; Food; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Streets/Roads; Religious Sites; Crowds
  - Manger Square, Bethlehem., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref214; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Bethlehem; Palestine; Religious Sites; Architecture; Churches; Outdoors; Men; Women; Children; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Church of the Nativity; Buildings
  - The Church of the Holy Sepulchre., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref215; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Churches; Jerusalem
  - People and vehicles on a roundabout., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref216; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Men; Women; Buses; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tel Aviv/Tall ʾabīb; Architecture; Shops; Bicycles/Tricycles; Children; Boys; Girls; Palestine; Transportation
  - People buying and selling fruit and vegetables in a side-street., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref217; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Women; Men; Streets/Roads; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Street Vendors; Markets; Buildings; Architecture; Palestine; Food
  - A fountain surrounded by trees., Circa 1930s - 1960s; ref218; Palphot, Tel Aviv; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Fountains; Men; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Children; Women; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Palm Trees; Architecture; Tel Aviv/Tall ʾabīb; Palestine; Parks
  - View of a corniche from the sea., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref219; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Tel Aviv/Tall ʾabīb; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; Buildings; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Landscapes; Architecture; Palestine
  - Portrait of a man in uniform in front of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref220; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Jerusalem; Men; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Palestine; Architecture; Religious Sites; Churches; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Outdoors; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers
  - A man in uniform standing on a stone platform., Circa 1940s - 1950s; ref221; The Matson Photo Service (Matson, G. Eric), Jerusalem, Palestine (1940s - 1970s); 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Jerusalem; Men; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Outdoors; Group Portraits; Streets/Roads
  - A round building with columns., Circa 1930s - 1960s; ref222; Palphot, Tel Aviv; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Buildings; Architecture; Tel Aviv/Tall ʾabīb; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Palestine
  - Christmas card with a photograph of Via Dolorosa., Circa 1930s - 1960s; ref223; Palphot, Tel Aviv; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Jerusalem; Christmas; Postcards; English Writing; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Women; Palestine; Religious Sites; Flower Garlands/Bouquets
  - Great Mosque of Damascus and Citadel of Aleppo., Circa 1890s - 1920s; ref224; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Aleppo, Syria; Damascus, Syria; Umayyad Mosque/Great Mosque of Damascus; Religious Sites; Buildings; Mosques; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Citadel of Aleppo
  - The Dome of the Rock., Circa 1890s - 1920s; ref225; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Jerusalem; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Palestine; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf
  - Views of Herod's Gate, the Church of Mary Magdalene and the Dome of the Rock., Circa 1890s - 1920s; ref226; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Religious Sites; Architecture; Churches; Mosques; Jerusalem; Palestine; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Landscapes; Mount of Olives/Jabal al-Zaytun, Jerusalem; Church of Mary Magdalene, Jerusalem; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Cemeteries; Gelatin Silver Prints
  - Damas Interieur de maison-Consul anglais Syria (Interior of a Damascene house in Syria), Circa 1890s - 1920s; ref227; Suleiman, Hakim, 1870s - 1880s; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Damascus, Syria; Houses; Albumen Prints; French Writing; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Tiles; Carpets/Rugs; Fountains; Furnishings; Architecture; Religious Sites
  - A group portrait of eighteen men in Jerusalem., 1865; ref228; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
    Albumen Prints; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Jerusalem; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Swords/Knives; Guns; Priests/Clergymen; Weapons; Canes/Walking Sticks; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Palestine; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Fez/Tarboush
  - Original content description of the collection, ref229; 1 Photographic Prints (E-records Digital copy only - AD_MC_030_ref194-ref229)
- Algeria, Yemen and Africa, ref716 (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
  - No.277 A narrow street in the Arab quarter in Algiers, Circa 1900 - 1920; ref230; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Algiers, Algeria; Children; Boys; Girls; Women; Men; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Outdoors
  - No.72 An aerial view of men in two boats in Tangier, Morocco, Circa 1900 - 1920; ref231; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Morocco; Men; Boats/Ships; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Seas; Morocco; Outdoors
  - No.276 Algiers - The Main street in the Arab Quarter, Circa 1900 - 1920; ref232; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Algiers, Algeria; Streets/Roads; Men; Women; Children; Crowds; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Boys; Cats; Animals; Architecture; Shops
  - No.82 A Tangier Scene, Circa 1900 - 1920; ref233; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Morocco; Streets/Roads; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Street Vendors; Architecture; Children; Boys; Shops
  - A crowd walking towards a mudbrick tower in Algeria, Circa 1900 - 1920; ref234; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Buildings; Architecture; Outdoors; Horses; Crowds; Men; Women; Children; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Algeria; Animals; Boys; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Group Portraits
  - An overhead view of a bay (no.5 Star Point) with buildings on land in Aden, Yemen., Circa 1870 - 1900; ref235; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Lighthouses; Houses; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Seas; Boats/Ships; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Aden, Yemen; Architecture; Landscapes; Streets/Roads; Mountains/Hills
  - A view of men on a sailboat, Circa 1870 - 1900; ref236; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Boats/Ships; Seas; Men; Outdoors; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Unknown Locations
  - A panoramic view of a few buildings on an island from sea, Circa 1870 - 1900; ref237; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Seas; Palm Trees; Houses; Buildings; Landscapes; Boats/Ships; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Unknown Locations
  - An overhead view of No.15 Aden Main street with mountains in the background, Circa 1870 - 1900; ref238; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Mountains/Hills; Crowds; Buildings; Street Vendors; Streets/Roads; Carriages/Coaches; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Landscapes; Aden, Yemen; Architecture
  - A panoramic view of buildings with mountains in the background in Aden, Yemen, Circa 1870 - 1900; ref239; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Mountains/Hills; Outdoors; Landscapes; Boats/Ships; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Aden, Yemen; Architecture
  - A general view of the Tanks and Cisterns in No. 10 Aden, Circa 1870 - 1900; ref240; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Architecture; Buildings; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Aden, Yemen; Outdoors
  - A view of tanks in No. 11 Aden with mountains in the background, Circa 1870 - 1900; ref241; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Construction; Albumen Prints; Men; Outdoors; Horses; Animals; Aden, Yemen; Landscapes
  - A panoramic view of camels in front of buildings and mountains., Circa 1870 - 1900; ref242; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Camels; Men; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Outdoors; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Animals; Outdoors; Landscapes; Aden, Yemen
  - A postcard of a portrait of a woman and children weaving beer strainers in Basutoland., Circa 1900 - 1930; ref243; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Children; Boys; Women; Houses; Postcards; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress; Lesotho; Outdoors; Children; Buildings; Group Portraits; Workers
  - A group portrait of a topless multigenerational group in front of a shelter., Circa 1900 - 1930; ref244; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Group Portraits; Men; Women; Children; Girls; Boys; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Houses; Regional/National Dress; Unknown Locations; Buildings; Turbans
  - A portrait of a man giving water to another man through a wooden water pipe., 1939-1945; ref245; Agence Trampus, 2 bis, Rue du Bouloi, Paris 1er; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Men; Water; Group Portraits; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Regional/National Dress; Unknown Locations
  - A couloir in the main street of Zanzibar, Circa 1890 - 1920; ref246; Photographic Publications Ltd, 110 Strand, London, WC2; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Signs/Signposts; Street Lamps; Streets/Roads; Men; Children; Buildings; Architecture; Zanzibar; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Boys
  - A portrait of a multigenerational group walking on a street with palm trees in the background in Zanzibar, Circa 1880 - 1920; ref247; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Palm Trees; Zanzibar; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Children; Men; Women; Boys; Girls; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Animals; Horses; Outdoors; Architecture
  - A portrait of two topless women wearing jewelry and adornments, in the background are piles of planks of wood., Circa 1880 - 1920; ref248; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Women; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Construction; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Unknown Locations; Buildings; Nude/Naked; Jewelry
  - A portrait of a topless washerman holding a water jug in his left hand., Circa 1900 - 1920; ref249; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)